ELIJAH THOMAS

38-56 Carling Avenue, Ottawa, Ontario (ON) · +(1) 5186520610 fayettebetty@gmail.com · www.linkedin.com/in/elijahthomas5515 · https://elithofan-portfolio.netlify.app

Elijah is a senior Full Stack Engineer with 5+ years of experience, having a passion for great software product, user friendly interfaces and good user experience. Considers him-self a self-motivated, fast-learner and problem-solver.

Worked with various Canada companies in the past and made great contributions to every stage of the development.

He has been focusing on designing and implementing full stack application using advanced web/mobile technologies and he doesn't hesitate to work on the most challenging part of the project to make my unique contribution.

He always thinks about the application from the user's point and can advise on the business side of the project.

EXPERIENCE

2016.9 - 2017.4

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERN, VITECONSULTING-CALGARY, AB CANADA

- Improved the codebase by following software engineering best practices
- Contributing automated testing and participating in team code reviews.
- Participated in API design and development of RESTful Services For the enterprise product in business.
- Collaborated and managed projects using Git, GitHub and Bitbucket.
- Automated unit and E2E testing and saving over 10h of work per week.
- Designed and implemented a RESTful API to connect the Amazon S3 service to store and retrieve customer data.

2017.7 - 2018.6

FULL STACK ENGINEER, SELF-EMPLOYED

Designed, built and maintained web applications, modeling tools, and high-quality deliverable.

- Worked on 3 MVPs while working with young startups and individual clients
- Built a fully-integrated one-to-one live video co-shopping platform for customers and associates using React, Next.js, TypeScript, and GraphQL
- Implemented work studio platform and OKR dashboard using React, TypeScript, AWS (lambda, API gateway, rest API, S3, Amplify), Node, MongoDB
- Built PWA for healthcare & fitness application using React, JavaScript, Ionic/React and several chrome extension apps in cross browsers

2018.8 - 2019.9

FULL STACK ENGINEER, OLD MOON DIGITAL-BURNABY CANADA

 Worked on building, shipping, and maintaining a single page application (React /Redux/TypeScript)

- Updated Vue based legacy platform into React/Redux based applications
- Built React based User Admin Portal that interfaced with AWS serverless to perform changes to user content
- Built RESTful APIs to automate real-time reporting of healthcare data to custom built dashboards improving trend prediction accuracy by 75%
- Delivered highly maintainable and reliable code using unit testing, integration testing, proper code documentation, and the best design patterns
- Worked on deconstructing complex features into actionable prioritized tasks with estimated timelines
- Setup storybook and built UI component libraries for global use following good code standard

2020.1 - 2022.3

FRONT-END WEB DEVELOPER, DATAROCKETS-TORONTO CANADA

- Involved in a real estate project that gives customers the ability to find perfect apartments
- Worked directly with clients to determine pain points in their jobs and deliver custom solutions to improve their ability to deliver finished products.
- Built an application to browse and watch videos using Next.js and streaming technology
- Participated in the initial wave of developers learning and utilizing React and Vue
- Created a web application which let customers efficiently browse media and buy them (Vue / Quasar)
- Collaborated with designers, back-end developers and UX experts to build, test and improve products
- Implemented SSR (server-side rendering) and SSG (static rendering) on Single Page Applications to increase SEO and initial page loading speed using Next.js and Gatsby.js.

2022.3 - 2022.9

NODE.JS BACKEND DEVELOPER, SELF-EMPLOYED

- Designed, implemented and integrated GraphQL APIs using Apollo, Nest.js, TypeORM, PostgreSQL
- Manipulated Chrome Profiler tools to improve the application performance
- Participated in code review and team design sessions
- Effectively communicated complex technical issues to other product and engineering teams Integrated third party APIs like Stripe APIs into the application
- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements
- Monitored and tracked server bugs on AWS CloudWatch and fixed them
- Used testing frameworks like Jest/Mocha to test APIs
- Performed migration from MySQL to MongoDB
- Worked on creating different type of indexes based on different collections to get good performance in MongoDB
- Containerized all the Ticketing related applications using Docker
- Managed Container using Docker by writing Dockerfiles and set up the automated build on Docker HUB and installed and configured kubernets Used infrastructure tools like Terraform and AWS.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

B.S., ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING & COMPUTER SCIENCE (2012-2016)

SKILLS

- JavaScript
- TypeScript
- PHP
- Python
- Java
- MySQL
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Css3
- Tailwind CSS
- Chakra UI
- MaterialUI

- React
- Vue.js
- Laravel
- AJAX
- Angular
- WordPress
- Magento
- HTML5
- Node.js
- Spring Boot
- Django
- Flask

LANGUAGES

• English-Fluent